Jaskaran Singh Software Developer

jaskarans880@gmail.com

♥ Waterloo,ON,Canada

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaskaran-singha593b710a/ 6478870265

https://jaskaransinghkohli.github.io/

nttps://github.com/jaskaransinghkohli



PROFILE

Mobile Solution Development Co-op Graduate and a software developer with hands-on experience gained through a growth-oriented internship during bachelor's and post-graduation degree in technology. Recognized by mentors and peers for demonstrating a strong passion for innovation and teamwork while working with a great organization as a java software developer. Winner of best Capstone Project in which around 100 students participated and my team was declared the only winner. It was a client project, and I was awarded for maintaining the agile methodology, best UI, best backend performance, and excellent presentation and technologies along with features used.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

01/2022 - 04/2022 Waterloo,ON, Canada

Java Software Developer Intern, Agfa Healthcare

- Effected in analysis, Java, Junit, Jboss, testing test cases for more than 50 packages.
- Read and understood server logs, test logs, and Jenkin logs for troubleshooting to make code effective by 100%.
- Added Server rules (ILMs) to make the server process effective by more than 2x.
- Deploying and maintaining a development sandbox to use for developing changes and running automated tests locally for 200+ user stories.
- Developed changes based on identified product needs or defects. Including committing code, responding to pull requests/review comments from other developers, and monitoring workflows for automated test results for 100% workflow
- Updated and added automated tests for complex workflows have more than 1200 tests related to the healthcare IT industry.

01/2020 - 04/2021

New Delhi, India

Software Developer, Percept Technologies ☑

- Developed UIs with JSP, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to make 90% more attractive applications.
- Implemented multi-threading and exception handling to improve application functionality. This helped improve the code efficiency by 95%.
- Developed both front-end and back-end using java spring boot to make the application 100% responsive.
- Underwent 50+ day learning session to know more about the processing of the product.

01/2018 - 06/2018

New Delhi, India

Software Developer Intern, Talent 4 Assure

- Studied Key Indicators for the level of web development for accessing 100% growth in the field.
- Worked on Server and Live Projects to have effective knowledge for 20+ products.
- Worked on JSP and Java Servlet and other beginner-level sessions for about 2 months.

SKILLS			
JAVA Web+Application	••••	HTML Frontend	••••
CSS Frontend	••••	MySQL Database	••••
C# Web+Desktop	••••	C++ App Development	••••
GIT Repository	••••	AGILE Methodology	••••
JIRA System	••••	UI/UX Designing	••••
Jenkins Logs and Processing	••••	Spring Boot	• • • • •

EDUCATION

05/2021 - 08/2022

Waterloo,ON, Canada

Post Graduation Mobile Solutions Development | Co-op, Conestoga College

- GPA: 3.95/4.0
- Best Capstone Project Award. Competition with more than 30 teams and 100+ students.
- Worked on various technologies making projects for industries and educative level.

08/2016 - 08/2020

Mohali, India

Bachelor's Computer Science and Technology, Chandigarh Group Of Colleges

- GPA: 8.9/10
- Research Paper with International Journals on Blue Brain Technology.
- Worked on various technologies making projects for industries and educative level.